[roaring]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
“The mysterious unknown.”
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words…
are called…
Hunters.
[theme song playing]
[seagull squawking]
LETTER x FROM x GON
"Dear Aunt Mito and Grandma.
How are you doing?
I’m doing pretty okay myself."
[chuckles]
"I just passed
the Third Phase of the Hunter Exam.
Isn't that great?
[in unison with Gon's voice] But it's been
pretty tough getting this far.
Right after I left the island...
[Gon's voice] the boat I was traveling on
ran into a really big storm.
[thunder]
[Gon] It wasn’t all bad, though.
That’s where I met Leorio and Kurapika.
If only you could buy class, as well.
Leorio.
That was strike three.
Step outside.
Time to finish off
the filthy Kurta bloodline
once and for all.
Take that back, Leorio!
I said take it back.
It’s Mister Leorio.
Take back what you said about my clan!
I will forgive you if you repent, Leorio.
You owe me an apology.
And I’m not telling you again.
I’m not repenting for anything, hear me?
Very well.
-[screaming]
-[gasps]
[both] Damn!
Thanks, Gon. You’re incredible!
You saved my life back there.
Well, I didn’t do it all alone.
Those two over there
helped rescue you too.
He’s right. Thank you both!
Please. No thanks necessary.
Yeah. No prob.
We’re just glad to see
you made it okay!
Me too!
In fact, I ought to get back to my post
right away!
[chuckles quietly]
[Kurapika giggles]
What’s so funny?
I’m embarrassed at my behavior.
Pardon my rudeness, Mister Leorio.
I wasn’t expecting that.
Just forget it.
You can drop the ‘Mister.’ Leorio’s fine.
I’m sorry, too.
And I take back everything
that I said to you before.
That was wrong of me.
[Gon] That’s what led to the three of us
traveling together
and we headed off
to find the site of the Hunter Exam.
[bird cawing]
[Gon] But...
the journey wasn’t easy at all.
Time for the exciting
multiple-choice quiz!
[various instruments play]
-And now here is your question.
-[beep]
You learn both your son and your daughter
have been kidnapped.
You will only be able
to rescue one of them.
Choose one for your son
and two for your daughter.
Which of these two will you rescue?
[growls]
[Leorio] She’s messing with us!
[roaring]
Out of the way, Kurapika!
This old hag needs to be taught a lesson
and I’m gonna make sure she gets it!
Would you please calm down?
How the hell do you expect me
to calm down?!
We got it right! Do you really want
to jeopardize that?
We did?
We’ve already given the correct response.
Silence.
Any other answer
would have been incorrect.
Please, save her!
You have to save my wife!
Leorio! See to his injuries.
Kurapika!
[sighs]
So… who’re you?
Hold on.
How can you tell that I’m not
the same one from before?
Huh? Oh, well, you look totally different.
Your voice is different, too.
It’s higher and kinda thinner.
[chortles]
[laughs loudly]
What’s up? Why are you laughing?
Is it something I said?
Your superhuman physical ability
and your powers of observation defy logic.
You, too, are worthy
to take the Hunter Exam.
So, you pass.
[Leorio chuckles]
[Gon] Then...
the Hunter Exam finally began!
I apologize for the delay.
Thank you for waiting.
The entry period for Hunter applicants
is officially closed.
So, with no further ado...
the Hunter Exam will now begin!
The first phase is quite simple.
All you have to do
is follow me to the second phase.
So, try to keep up.
[Gon] That’s when I made friends
with a boy I met.
His name’s Killua
and he’s about the same age as me.
-[Killua] Hey. How old are you?
-Twelve years old.
Same as me.
I think I’ll run for a little while.
Whoa! Cool!
My name’s Killua.
Hi, I’m Gon!
[Gon]
Hey why do you want to be a Hunter anyway?
Who, me?
I never said I wanted to be a Hunter.
I just heard the Exam
was supposed to be really hard.
It sounded kinda fun, so here I am.
But it’s not as fun as I thought.
What about you?
[Gon]
Well, the thing is my dad’s a Hunter.
So, I decided I was gonna be a Hunter
just like him, no matter what!
[Killua] Hmm.
So, what kind of Hunter is he?
[Gon] No idea.
-It’s the weirdest thing I’ve ever heard!
-Huh?
You want to be the same kind of Hunter
as your dad
but you don’t know anything about him?
That’s nuts!
Mito’s the one who raised me
and she told me a little,
but I’ve only ever seen him in pictures
she showed me from a long time ago.
-Wait, so who’s Mito?
-She’s my aunt.
Ah.
She said that my dad took the Hunter Exam
when he was only 12 years old, too.
He passed his first try
and became a Hunter.
That's when he decided
to leave the island.
So, I came here in order to find out
why he chose being a Hunter
over staying at home with me.
Hm...
[examinee] The exit!
Oh, thank goodness!
[both] Goal!
Yeah! I did it! I finished first!
What are you talking about? I totally won.
Now, let’s go over the rules of the game.
All you have to do
is simply take this ball away from me.
If you can do that
before the airship arrives, you win.
[both] I’ve almost got it!
[Gon] Whoa!
Well now.
Excellent teamwork!
You get an ‘A’ for effort!
The Hunter Exam’s...
[in unison with Gon's voice]
...been a lot of fun with Killua around.
We’re best friends now,
so that’s pretty cool.
HUNTER GLOSSARY
LETTER
[Gon] Besides Killua,
there are applicants
from all over the world
who came to take the Hunter Exam,
so there are lots of amazing people.
[appreciative exhale]
Not bad,
little boy.
Is that a fishing pole?
How original!
I’d like to see it. Do you mind?
[Leorio] Leave him alone.
[yells] Your fight’s with me!
[roaring]
[Hisoka]
Did you come here to help your friend?
[gasps]
Such a good boy.
I adore that look.
[grunting]
Well done.
I’m beginning to get excited.
[roaring]
[Gon choking]
[Hisoka] It’s so delightful.
I love that look!
[coughing]
[Hisoka] Don't worry.
I didn’t kill your friend.
He’s going to be just fine.
And that’s because he passed!
[Hisoka chuckling]
And yes.
You pass as well.
Now, go and become a good Hunter.
[Gon] But I’ve gotta say.
It was actually pretty exciting
back there.
I was so scared that all I wanted to do
was run away.
But I couldn’t.
‘cause I was excited at the same time.
Isn’t that weird?
There were 404 applicants
at the start of the Hunter Exam
but by the time
we reached the Third Phase,
there were only 41 left.
[Beans] Ah… Ahem.
Everyone. This is the site
of the Exam’s Third Phase.
You’ll be competing here
at the top of the Trick Tower.
Did you say, ‘Trick Tower’?
[Beans] In order to pass this Phase
you must
reach the base of the tower alive.
The time limit is 72 hours.
[Leorio] Whoa. Where the hell are we?
See that? Over there.
[Lippo] Gentlemen, let me explain.
You’ve probably already noticed
that some of the prisoners of Trick Tower
are standing before you.
Not just prisoners.
The Hunter Exam Committee
has also officially hired them on
as Examiners.
In this Phase you’ll be fighting
against all five of them.
Without knowing what’s up their sleeves,
there’s far too much at stake.
-Given that, I’ll-
-[Tonpa] Nope. I’ll go.
Mister Tonpa?
[Tonpa grunting]
[Bendot] Begin!
[growling]
[yells] I... give up!
Huh?
What?
Did he just...
say that he gives up?
Uh maybe he meant ‘give me a sec’…
[chuckles lightly]
We each light a candle at the same time
and whoever’s candle goes out first
is the loser.
[startled cry]
Hey. Take a look at Gon’s candle.
The flame suddenly got a lot stronger!
I should’ve known.
He somehow laced Gon’s candle
with gunpowder or some other accelerant.
That’s why it’s burning so much faster!
I guess now that the flame’s burning
so much stronger,
it’ll take a lot more than a little breeze
to put it out.
[Sedokan gasps]
He’s fast!
[Gon blows the candle]
[chuckles]
I win!
Look at his tattoo;
it’s a spider with twelve legs!
And that means…
Name’s Majitani!
I’m one of the Phantom Troupe’s
four devas!
That first strike
was just an introduction.
This is your last chance to give up.
If you do, I’m still willing to...
Hey… What’s wrong with you?
What are you--
Huh?
[strangled cries]
All right! I know what we’re betting on!
Let’s bet on
who’ll win rock paper scissors!
[giggles]
Hey, what’s so funny?
[Leroute] It’s just I can already tell
what you’re going to use.
I’m something of a mind reader, you see.
That’s a lie!
You can bluff all you want,
but it’ll take a lot more than that
to scare me!
You’ll believe it soon…
[grunts]
-You ready?
-[cries out]
And rock! Paper!
[both] Scissors!
[Leroute] Well? What’ll you use next?
Come on. Think hard.
[Leroute laughs]
Damn it! [grunts]
[screaming]
What is happening?!
Here we go!
Here comes the draw!
[laughs]
I win! Yay!
How do you wanna do this?
[man] Do this?
You have the wrong idea.
See, you’re about to be on the wrong side
of a one-sided massacre.
I don’t care about the Exam
or reducing my sentence.
All I want is to hear you scream.
Really? Fine.
We’ll just keep fighting
until one of us dies.
That’s right. A battle to the death.
Soon... I’ll tear your body apart
with just my bare hands. You got it?
[heart beating]
[all gasp]
That’s mine.
[grunts]
It belongs to me.
Give it back.
Give it to me.
[announcer] Please select a path.
There are two available options
to choose from.
The long and difficult path
which the entire group can take,
or the short and easy path
which will be limited
to only three of you.
I’m going to press ‘O’.
It’s just we all made it this far
by working together.
We should finish together.
Gon…
[Gon] It’s a big risk. I know that.
But still, we’ve got to try!
[grunting]
[Gon]
We entered the long and difficult path,
broke down the wall
and from there,
we snuck into the short and easy one.
Boy, my butt hurts!
I certainly wasn’t expecting
the short and easy path to be a slide.
[Hisoka] Three of them, eh?
[announcer] Thirty seconds remain.
Even with that big slide,
that was really close!
My hands are covered in blisters.
[Leorio] Same here.
[announcer] Leorio, number 403,
is the twenty-third to pass.
My hands are wrecked
but all five of us
cleared the tower together, didn’t we?
And it’s all thanks to Gon!
[long signal sounds]
[announcer] The Third Phase
of the Hunter Exam is over!
Twenty-five applicants have passed,
including one deceased.
[Gon] That’s pretty much it, Aunt Mito.
That’s how I completed
the Third Phase of the Exam.
I don’t know how many phases
are left to go
but I’m gonna pass every last one of ‘em.
‘cause I’m gonna be a Hunter...
just like Dad.
Until next time!
Gon Freecss.
[Mito] Well, did you hear that, Ging?
It looks like your son is following
in your footsteps.
So? Are you happy?
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time: "Hit x The x Target!"
A sneaky hit!
[Hisoka] Hit and run.